## KANG HONG JIN

Ph.D Candidate School of Computing and Information Systems Singapore Management University hjkang.2018@phdcs.smu.edu.sg https://kanghj.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in improving developer productivity by designing better ways of mining abstractions of software systems. In the course of my research, I hope to address important and practical problems. In my PhD, my work focused on bugs and vulnerabilities related to the use of APIs and third-party code, e.g., libraries.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Ph.D

Jan 2019 – Jan 2023 (expected) School of Computing and Information Systems Singapore Management University

#### **BACHELOR OF COMPUTING**

2012 – 2016 School of Computing National University of Singapore First Class Honours/Highest Distinction

## PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE/JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

#### **Compressing Pre-trained Models of Code into 3 MB**

Jieke Shi, Zhou Yang, Bowen Xu, **Hong Jin Kang**, David Lo *IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering 2022 (ASE 2022)* 

#### **AutoPruner: Tranformer-based Call Graph Pruning**

Le-Cong Thanh, **Hong Jin Kang**, Truong Giang Nguyen, Stefanus Agus Haryono, David Lo, Xuan-Bach D. Le, Huynh Quyet Thang.

ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering 2022 (ESEC/FSE 2022)

### Test Mimicry to Assess the Exploitability of Library Vulnerabilities.

**Hong Jin Kang**, Truong Giang Nguyen, Xuan-Bach D. Le, Corina Pasareanu, David Lo. *ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA 2022)*.

Detecting False Alarms from Automatic Static Analysis Tools: How Far are We? Hong Jin Kang, Khai Loong Aw, and David Lo.

IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering 2022 (ICSE 2022)

(Nominated for a Distinguished Paper Award)

### **HERMES:** Using Commit-Issue Linking to Detect Vulnerability-Fixing Commits

Truong Giang Nguyen, **Hong Jin Kang**, David Lo, Sharma Abhishek, Santosa Andrew, Sharma Asankhaya, and Ming Yi Ang.

IEEE International Conference on Software Analysis, Evolution and Reengineering 2022 (SANER 2022)

# Active Learning of Discriminative Subgraph Patterns for API Misuse Detection Hong Jin Kang, David Lo.

IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE)

### Adversarial Specification Mining

Hong Jin Kang, David Lo.

ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM)

#### **IoTBox: Sandbox Mining to Prevent Interaction Threats in IoT Systems**

Hong Jin Kang, Sheng Qin Sim, David Lo

IEEE International Conference on Software Testing, Verification and Validation 2021 (ICST 2021)

# AndroEvolve: Automated Android API Update with Data Flow Analysis and Variable Denormalization

Stefanus A Haryono, Ferdian Thung, David Lo, Lingxiao Jiang, Julia Lawall, **Hong Jin Kang,** Lucas Serrano, Gilles Muller

Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE)

# BiasFinder: Metamorphic test generation to uncover bias for sentiment analysis systems.

Muhammad Hilmi Asyrofi, Zhou Yang, Imam Nur Bani Yusuf, **Hong Jin Kang**, Ferdian Thung, and David Lo

IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE)

### CC2Vec: Distributed representations of code changes,

Thong Hoang, Hong Jin Kang, Julia Lawall, David Lo.

ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering 2020 (ICSE 2020)

# **Towards Generating Transformation Rules without Examples for Android API Replacement**

Ferdian Thung, Hong Jin Kang, Lingxiao Jiang, David Lo.

*IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution 2019 (ICSME 2019)* 

#### Assessing the Generalizability of code2vec Token Embeddings

Hong Jin Kang, Tegawende F Bissyandé., David Lo.

ACM/IEEE International Conference on Automated Software Engineering 2019 (ASE 2019)

#### **Semantic Patches for Java Program Transformation**

**Hong Jin Kang**, Ferdian Thung, Julia Lawall, Gilles Muller, Lingxiao Jiang, David Lo. *European Conference on Object-Oriented Programming 2019 (ECOOP 2019)* 

#### **SHORT PAPERS**

#### AndroEvolve: Automated Update for Android Deprecated-API Usages

by Stefanus Agus Haryono, Ferdian Thung, David Lo, Lingxiao Jiang, Julia Lawall, **Hong Jin Kang**, Lucas Serrano, Gilles Muller

ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering 2021 (ICSE 2021) – Demonstrations

# BugsInPy: a database of existing bugs in Python programs to enable controlled testing and debugging studies

Ratnadira Widyasari, Sheng Qin Sim, Camellia Lok, Haodi Qi, Jack Phan, Qijin Tay, Constance Tan, Fiona Wee, Jodie Ethelda Tan, Yuheng Yieh, Brian Goh, Ferdian Thung, **Hong Jin Kang**, Thong Hoang, David Li, Eng Lieh Ouh

ACM Joint Meeting on European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE 2020) Tool Demo

# **Automatic Android Deprecated-API Usage Update by Learning from Single Updated Example**

Stefanus Agus Haryono, Ferdian Thung, **Hong Jin Kang**, Lucas Serrano, Gilles Muller, Julia Lawall, David Lo, Lingxiao Jiang.

International Conference on Program Comprehension 2020 - Early Research Achievements. 2020 (ICPC ERA 2020)

# A Comparison of Word Embeddings for English and Cross-Lingual Chinese Word Sense Disambiguation

**Hong Jin Kang,** Tao Chen, Muthu Kumar Chandrasekaran, Min-Yen Kan. The COLING Workshop on Natural Language Processing Techniques for Educational Applications Workshop (NLP-TEA-3 2016)

#### **SERVICE**

JOURNAL REVIEWER: EMSE, TOSEM, IST

**SUB-REVIEWER:** ICSME 2020, APSEC 2020, MSR 2020, ASE 2021,

ICST 2022, ICSE 2022

**PROGRAM COMMITTEE:** SANER ERA 2023

#### MENTORED STUDENTS

I had the privilege of working with other students/junior researchers, including

Aw Khai Loong undergraduate student

• Sim Sheng Qin undergraduate student

• Jonathan Ooi masters student

Le Cong Thanh research engineer, starting a PhD in Jan 2023

Truong Giang Nyugen

 research engineer

research engineer

Stefanus Agus Haryono research engineer

#### **AWARDS**

2022 SMU Dean's List 2020, 2021, 2022 SMU's Presidential Doctoral Fellowship

#### WORKING EXPERIENCE

### AUG 2018 – DEC 2018 RESEARCH ENGINEER, SMU

 Developed Coccinelle4J, a port of Coccinelle for the Java programming language. Coccinelle is a widely adopted program matching and transformation tool for C systems software, including the Linux kernel. Over 6000 commits have been in the Linux kernel with the help of Coccinelle in the past 10 years. We apply Coccinelle4J to the automatic migration of deprecated Android API usages.

#### 2018

### **BACKEND ENGINEER, GRAB**

- Worked with cutting-edge tools and managed cloud-based infrastructure.
- Owned a microservice on the critical path of all bookings. Improved testing to identify single points of failure, improving the resilience of the service to ensure uptime and SLAs are met.

#### 2016 - 2018

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WORKS APPLICATIONS CO. LTD**

- Worked on enterprise-grade HR Enterprise Resource Management software.
- Mentored junior engineers.
- Full-stack development from the back-end using Spring, management of Cassandra, Elasticsearch, to implementing a new user experience on the front-end with modern frameworks.

### AUG 2015 – MAY 2016 STUDENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TEAMMATES @ NUS

- Involved in both planning and development of the project. Planned and managed weekly releases.
- Part of the team that introduced static analysis tools and CI to the project.

# MAY 2014 – AUG 2014 INTERN, TEAMIE

• Developed several new features, including a feature that summarizes users' activity logs to identify highlights of their history on the platform.